Visit our website for more: turkision.com
No living being was harmed during
the filming of this series.
Yenişehir
Episode 121
Alps, hey!
Do not oppress the prisoners.
Take these people to the dungeon now.
Bandage their wounds.
After beheading Nayman...
If there are people whose ransom
will be paid, they will be set free.
If there are those among them who want
to repent and enter the religion of Islam...
we need their clothes, come on.
Your command, my Bey.
Brothers.
Are you okay, brothers?
Are you okay?
We'll be fine.
How is he, Kumral Abdal?
Tell me.
He will be fine, my Bey.
He will be fine, Inshallah.
Yes, we will be fine, Inshallah.
Inshallah.
My Bey.
Nayman and his army lifted
the siege and withdrew.
It will be the last war.
Let him do whatever he wants.
Say what you need to say.
Malhun Hatun sent word
from the Kargın tribe.
And yet?
Aktemur Bey.
He sat on the seat of lordship in
the tribe of Kargın, my Bey.
What?
- Boran.
- My Bey.
Summon the Beys...
to meet in the court.
Summon Aktemyr from the Kargın tribe.
And let the rest come
with me to the palace.
Your command, my Bey.
Hold on, Alps!
You struggle.
This is my area and you have
no escape from here.
We didn't come to run away,
we came to take your soul, Saveli.
I will cut off your head!
Protect your back.
Come on
They are everywhere, my Sultan.
You will kill all the snakes in this palace!
Where is Bala Hatun?
We parted ways and she is also looking for
the Sultan Aladdin.
They said, don't say big words.
You said you'd cut off my head, right?
Look whose neck the sword touches.
Move while you have the chance.
I will not ask you for
mercy in order to live.
No.
I will not stain my hands with your blood.
Sultan Aladdin will kill you.
Sultan Aladdin will kill you, not me, Saveli.
Your betrayal has been exposed.
Who attacked the palace with his
sword, Bala Hatun? You or me?
This is the evidence of the blood
that was shed in this palace.
What's going on?
What's the matter?
This is the traitor who tried
to kill Sultan Aladdin.
They arrested her.
Come on, move.
It doesn't end here, Saveli.
I will break your bones! Leave me!
You, come here.
Take a unit with you.
And take İsmihan and bring
her to me, come on.
Come on, soldiers.
Nayman made me an offer.
He wants to duel me face to face.
Why, my Bey?
If I defeat him...
his soldiers will leave this land.
But if he defeats me...
Beys and Alps
will pledge allegiance to him.
Can Nayman be trusted, my Bey?
Even if you kill him...
he must have given his soldiers orders
to destroy everything on these lands.
He will keep his promise.
As long as we know he's
going to cheat us...
let us do the same.
Let's attack first.
Even if they will resort to subterfuge...
We must take our precautions.
How we defended Yenişehir...
we will defend all our
properties, as we did in Yenişehir.
Yenişehir resisted because you are here.
But other properties...
You won't be able to stand it.
Let's see.
Karacahisar.
Kulucahisar.
Hisar.
İnegöl.
Bilecik.
Söğüt.
Villages adjacent to
these properties as well...
these will be our defensive campaigns
there.
Look at it well, Alps.
They are the places where
the warriors will settle...
and the places where
the gunpowder will be placed.
They are all drawn on maps.
These show the Beys
who will preside over the property...
but...
This is Marmaracık's defense plan.
It was not for us to give it to Öktem Bey.
We will not leave
Marmaracık to the infidels.
Excuse me, my Bey, but
when did you get this ready?
We rest only for a short time
so that the whole Islamic world can rest.
We will fight a war where there is no rest anymore.
Be prepared.
This is our defensive campaign.
Now it is the turn of our
offensive campaign.
Karancu.
You will send three messengers
to the regions of the Beys.
I want all soldiers
over there to come here....
secretly.
When Osman dies...
they will spread my wrath on this land.
Shaman.
As soon as possible...
Prepare a poison that will prevent
Osman's eyes from seeing.
Nayman, who defeated the Beys,
will withdraw his soldiers from their lands to ours.
He will set up camp for them here.
Let's be there for him.
And let's pounce on them.
No, we will not attack them.
Right now, it looks like Nayman
will keep his promise.
For this reason, he would not reveal
the location of his camp.
But to find out where the units that
will attack us are stationed...
Warriors will be sent to those areas.
When units start attacking...
Warriors (Alps) will attack those camps.
Come on, let everyone go to work.
Duran.
My Bey.
I have to fight Nayman.
Look.
Is he thinking of a trick?
Find out.
Your command, my Bey
Öktem tribe
Won't you bless Aktemur, Hatuns?
Ayşe Hatun.
Why is your face so frowning?
What is so sad about this?
He is my son.
I deal with him as I like.
Aktemur.
Do you know what you did?
These things are always
your idea, Bengi Hatun.
You should have consulted
Osman Bey before, Aktemur.
It is enough!
My mother.
My uncle's wife.
I am not a child.
I know what I'm doing.
And you both know that I have
become the Bey of the Kargın tribe.
Aktemur.
We know, we know.
But, know this...
The news must have reached Osman Bey
by now.
Let's see if you can speak
comfortably in front of him like this.
It is true that I sat on the chair
without telling my uncle.
But there is nothing wrong with this.
Aktemur.
The wrong thing is not you
sitting on the chair.
Rather, it is you moving
according to your whims.
If there's a campaign or something
you know of, let us know.
Otherwise, the end of this matter is bad.
Has the sovereign's seat
ever been left empty, Malhun Hatun?
I am responsible for the result
of the work I have done.
And I have an answer for every question.
May I come in, my Bey?
Come in.
My Bey.
Osman Bey has sent news.
He is waiting for you in the Divan.
Ready my horse, let's get out quickly.
Your command, my Bey.
- Sultan...
- Shut up!
You will tell me all the things
that happen in my palace.
Whether your heads stay in place depends
on what you're going to say.
If you say the words incompletely...
I will hang your head at
the entrance to Konya.
You tell me first, Vizier.
My Sultan, Osman Bey is
after rebellion again.
And now he has sent his wife to kill you.
He is lying, my Sultan.
Actually, the one who wants to
kill you is Saveli.
His loyalty is not to you.
It's for Nayman.
Osman Bey has warned you.
I'm tired of these games.
I will not give you my soul...
nor my throne.
You cannot see the traitor
standing before your eyes.
Mother Sultan.
She's in the palace now.
Where?
Is there no end to the lies you tell
to survive, Bala Hatun?
My Sultan, let me
cut off her head now!
Traitor, you will be
drenched in your own blood.
If something happens, we'll kill Sultan Aladdin
and Bala at the same moment, get ready.
Now!
You will not be able to escape my wrath!
I thought you would
never come, Mother Sultan.
The snake's head is here, but the tail is
everywhere, Bala Hatun!
You will not escape my wrath, Sultan.
I'm sending your head to Nayman.
If it weren't for this brave warrior of Osman,
we wouldn't have been able to get here.
The price of betrayal is your soul.
If I could kill you and take Konya,
all the people would be forgiven.
Now, in order to take Konya,
all the people must be killed.
Whoever seeks my soul
will first lose his soul.
And whoever thinks of killing the people
will not even have a grave.
Are you okay, my Sultan?
I'm fine, mother.
Fine.
We can't trust anyone.
They nested everywhere in the palace.
I will crush all of their heads.
Bring everyone in front of me whoever was
sending regards to Saveli...
and all those who stand behind him.
Everyone has value in his own eyes.
I want them all.
Your command, my Sultan.
I will behead them all.
Osman Bey is coming!
Salam Alaikum.
Alaikum Salam.
Please be seated.
The court opened with the ninety-nine
names of Allah Almighty...
who made us responsible for
war, not for victory.
In the name of Allah, the most
gracious, the most merciful.
Tell me now, what is the condition of our country?
You tell me, Uraz Bey.
My Bey.
People aren't fine at all.
Nayman's presence has
harmed the business.
Bayram Bey.
You tell me.
The situation is the same
in Kulucahisar, my Bey.
One complaint.
Convoys no longer pass through
and trade has stopped.
Well, what about the tribes?
What are the conditions of the tribes?
My Bey.
The people of the tribe take the goods to the city
and bring them back without selling them.
Merchants do not have the
power to buy and sell.
They all say the same
thing to the tribesmen.
"Our profit is not enough to buy"
Don't you have anything to say?
The chief of the army who was not at the head
of his army when they defended Yenişehir.
Don't you have anything to say?
You don't even know the condition
of the people you rule.
What is your advantage?
Is it leaving me alone?
Did you ask my permission to
remove you from your job?
Did I make you sit in that chair?
My Bey, I sat on it so the
chair wouldn't be empty.
You were my nephew at your first mistake.
I forgave you with one slap.
However...
You have no place in my
family or in the court.
Get out now.
My Bey.
Get out!
The situation of the people is difficult.
Tell me.
What measures have you
taken in this regard?
We met with the elders of the Achaeans, and took
aid to the merchants from the treasury.
You're just killing flies.
The main issue is draining the swamp.
We're ready to do as you command, my Bey.
These problems will surely be solved
But you never talk about the matter
of Nayman.
- Boran.
- My Bey.
Hand out the maps relating to Nayman.
Your command, my Bey.
Beys, look at the maps carefully.
Defense plans are all in these maps.
Consult well with the Beys.
And tomorrow you will be in the
field of war with your armies.
However...
It's clear that the main distress is
with the people.
We will now be on their side.
I would even go to them
myself and see their problems.
And you too will come with me in disguise.
You will spread among the people
and get to know all their problems one by one.
The distress of the people is more
important than the affliction of Nayman.
Court is over.
Summon Malhun Hatun.
Your command, my Bey.
Marmaracık Castle
Tell me.
Your army is out on the
road, Commander Nayman.
I'm not asking about
the situation out there.
They will come from everywhere.
Tell me about the situation inside.
Aktemur, nephew of Osman.
He sat on Öktam's chair without
Osman's knowledge.
Aktemur wants to fly on his wings, then.
And what does his uncle say about this?
Osman held a court.
Aktemur was also summoned to the court.
He clearly acknowledges
Aktemur's sovereignty.
Osman will never accept the sovereignty of Aktemur.
His pride prevents this.
Commander Nayman, there is news
from our spies in Yenişehir, sir.
They heard it while people were
talking about it in the bazaar.
Osman expelled Aktemur from the Court.
Osman
walks alone into my fist.
If you'll excuse me...
I want to talk to you alone about
a topic, Sultan.
Say it.
Nayman's intention is to take over our
vast lands, my Sultan.
For this reason, he wanted to kill you.
Nayman won't stop until he's done.
In this situation...
I have neither the strength nor
the ability to face Nayman, Bala Hatun.
It is not important, my Sultan.
What you have is enough for us.
The believers defeated the unbelieving
many times.
Living under Nayman's
banner is not a solution.
Rebellion against the
oppressor is part of faith.
There is news from the
borderlands, Mother Sultan.
Osman and Nayman will fight.
Alright.
We'll go to the borderlands without
wasting any time, Celali.
Do your preparations.
They will fight.
And we'll share what's left.
You start the war first...
and you gather allies
after that, Bala Hatun.
I will give Osman Bey
five thousand soldiers...
and twenty wagons of arms
in case of war.
Thank you, Sultan.
The army you provide will
be a means for good.
Now...
I have another request from you.
What more do you ask for, Bala Hatun?
I need you to write a letter
to Ghazan Khan.
What letter is this?
What is your intention?
My intention is executing...
the campaign that will end the war before
it begins, by order of Osman Bey.
Kurudere Location
- Salam Alaikum.
- Alaikum Salam.
Come on, I have fabrics.
This is good
Cut this.
How is the business?
Thank Allah very
much, my Bey, we are managing.
There's nothing left on
your table but hemp cloths.
Don't you have velvet fabrics?
Where do I get it, my sister?
Merchants come and offer us velvet fabrics.
They then lead their caravans
to Bursa and Iznik.
We do not have the
possibility to buy velvet fabrics.
What breaks your strength?
War first, then shop rent.
I earn forty coins or hardly earn them
I pay twenty of them as rent for the shop.
- May Allah help you.
- Thank you.
Cut a little bit of this cloth.
They will look at us and go as long
as we don't have the goods, brother.
We hardly pay the rent for the shops.
We can't manage things with what we have.
We will close the shops before
the end of this month, brother.
- Here you go, sister.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Yes, tell me what puts you in
such a difficult situation?
What puts you in such distress?
Not what, but who, my Bey.
Who is he?
It's Osman Bey.
Osman Bey, then.
And what did Osman Bey do?
What can Osman Bey do?
The infidels pounced on our heads.
Trade stopped and revenues decreased,
but expenses did not decrease, my sister.
Rents have weighed heavily
on our shoulders.
Who is the commander of this district?
It's Osman Bey.
Can't he protect the merchants?
Halil.
Osman Bey will fight the head
of the infidels Nayman soon.
Will he still have time for
us while he sharpens swords?
You're right, blacksmith.
No, Halil says the right thing.
If you let all these enemies
come after you...
and take care of external
problems for the sake of a dream..
You should take care of
internal problems as well.
Look, the Bey understood me and you didn't.
Say, is this the case for all merchants?
This is the condition of all merchants who
do not have their shops, my Bey.
Okay.
Bring death!
Shaman.
Is the poison ready yet?
It'll be ready
tomorrow, Commander Nayman.
Tonight...
Patience increases the effect
of the poison.
This poison will bring
disability and death to Osman.
And the verdict is mine.
I will kill Osman with this poison.
But it will end tonight.
My army shall gather tomorrow,
and the seal shall be in my hands.
All Mongols will unite behind me.
Then I will not only wipe out Osman alone
from these lands, but all the Turks.
Konya, the border regions
and the whole world will belong to me!
All your soldiers are
eagerly awaiting this, sir.
Sacrifice horses.
All soldiers will drink
horse blood tonight.
They will dedicate it to
the god of heaven.
When victory is mine tomorrow...
I will drink the blood that will flow from
Osman's head and offer it to the God of Heaven.
Come on, pay the tribute.
What tribute?
I can't even pay my shop rent.
What do we have to do
with your rent?
Either you pay tribute or
you give up your life.
Don't do it, Aghas.
Prepare the double next time.
Otherwise, we wouldn't be
content with taking your soul.
Ali Agha.
Is your tribute (tax) ready?
Don't do it, what tribute?
Aren't you afraid for your son, Ali?
Father, don't.
Good.
I break that hand that extends to
what does not belong to you.
Are you the one who will break it?
Yes, I will break it.
Come here, walk.
If I see you here again....
It didn't end here.
He's still talking!
Walk!
He's still talking.
Are you okay?
May Allah be pleased with you, my Bey.
May Allah be pleased with you too.
Who are you? Where did you come from
and where are you going?
We come from Allah and return to Him.
We are traveling.
Yes, we all come from Him
and return to Him.
But not all of us have these advantages.
Say it, and who are you?
We came here to ask for work, but...
when we saw your condition
like this, we couldn't say it.
Anyway, may Allah make it easy for
all of you, we have a long way to go.
Come on, Hatun.
It's true what you say, we
have no work to do for you.
But we also don't allow travelers
to leave hungry like that.
Especially in the time of
blessed Ramadan and after what you did.
Hatun, he's inviting us to iftaar.
So, let's go, my Bey.
Good.
Halil, run home and tell your mother.
Tell her we have two guests, come on, son.
Come on traveler, there's a
little left for iftaar.
Help me to pack up the shop.
Come on, then.
I will not allow anyone to say that
Ali Agha left his guests hungry.
- Come on, then.
- Take this.
Damascus
This is where the deal was
made with Bayındır.
We'll wait.
Talay must be waiting for me.
Are you the merchant?
Yes. It's me.
Follow us, merchant.
Only you
Soldier, watch your treatment of
Nayman's obedient servant.
The price of your insolence will be
your beheading, to say the least.
Either I come with my men, or I don't.
Go tell Talay.
Talay, the merchant just said.
My men are no different from me.
If the merchant
comes, they will come with him.
Otherwise, he will not come.
How do I know you're
not playing a game?
I tell you I come up with the name Nayman,
and you still say it's a game.
Look at this.
How many of these are there in the world?
He gave it to me.
You're making me wait for no reason, soldier.
That's an insult.
And the insult directed at me is
directed at Nayman, too, so you know that.
What are you going to do?
Oh my.
Hüseyin.
When we save ourselves, Inshallah...
remind me to kill you before Nayman.
Sir, I don't understand
what you are saying.
And what do you understand, Hüseyin?
What do you understand?
But I'll explain and I'll
cut off your head.
My Bey.
My head is for you.
But if you're talking about catching us,
they slipped like snakes.
I never noticed they were after us.
No!
But you had to watch out, Hüseyin.
Look, we didn't have the ingot anymore,
and we couldn't solve the Damascus thing.
We only have our heads above our bodies.
And that's because of
Osman's justice.
However, Hüseyin...
I think it's time to run away.
Warrior brother, come a little.
You arrested us and tied us here
since the morning while we were fasting.
Untie us a little, so that the
blood flows through our bodies.
Sit quietly and don't make me kill you.
Well, we made a
mistake, but we are not infidels.
Have pity on us, brother warrior.
Thank Turgut Bey that he
left you to be judged by Osman Bey.
You want to rest.
You will rest when you die.
I ask for Allah's forgiveness
and repent to Him.
You are a Muslim and I am a Muslim.
Pity us a little.
At least change the location of the rope.
You traitor.
The other is coming, my Bey!
I repent to Him.
And we are fasting!
Hüseyin Bey.
This means that if we depended
on you, we would not survive.
Let's go, he's passed out,
let's go before he gets him back.
We have to make them lose
track of us as soon as possible.
- Come on, my Bey.
- Come on.
Did Osman Bey
get very angry?
He didn't stop at anger, Alçiçek.
He kicked me out of the court.
He kicked me out of the court in
front of all those Alps and Beys.
What do you say, Aktemur?
Yes, mother.
My uncle accuses me
of neglecting my mission.
I was not even allowed to speak.
Don't bow your head.
If your uncle isn't
behind you, I'm here, son.
And the Kargın tribe, too.
I know, mother, I know.
I will not disappoint you.
This is not the time to stop.
I had made a promise to Kargın Beys
before you sat in the chair of Beyhood.
Promise what, mother?
Since the seat of sovereignty
has found its owner...
the time has come for revenge for
dear Öktam and the warriors.
Mother.
I say we'll take Marmaracık from the hand
of that dishonorable Nayman, Alçiçek.
That coward killed our Bey and our
warriors and took our property.
We will not sit still like this.
Right?
No.
Our wound is recent.
And Aktemur just became a Bey.
Is there an old and new rule?
It is not right for us to stop now.
Do you want us to break our
promise from day one?
Aktemur, do you think like Alçiçek?
As long as there is a promise made...
We'll take Marmaracık.
And we will take revenge of
Öktem Bey and our warriors.
Mashallah! We will definitely take it.
We will take it, Inshallah.
Osman.
Was this a good time for a secret search?
This is exactly the time.
Well, what about Nayman?
Don't you trust your Bey?
I certainly trust you, my dear Osman.
You are the only one I trust.
Don't act like you don't know.
Thank you.
I will be victorious, Inshallah.
But you say what if it happened otherwise?
Whatever happens.
We're mortal, Malhun.
The state will remain.
What makes a state a state are the people.
I want to see them.
I want to see them, Malhun.
Is it okay, son?
I know who you are.
I'm traveling, son.
I am a traveler.
Tell me, who am I?
You are Osman Bey.
I don't forget the person after I see him.
I saw you on horseback in Söğüt.
And when I saw you fight, I made sure.
Come see, come.
Well, did you tell your mother
and father about me?
Is this why the table is
in this condition?
No, this table is like this for everyone.
Well, what about the words
you said in the market square?
Did you know me then?
If I didn't know that the one standing
in front of me was Osman Bey...
why should I even speak?
Now...
This will be a secret between you and me.
- State secret.
Okay.
The table of the poor shall be like this.
No, no.
Mashallah, it is more beautiful
and blessed than many tables.
Yes.
Yenişehir/ Osman Bey's palace
How much time is
left for iftaar, Cerkutay?
I don't feel well.
Look at you.
Look at the situation he's gotten
himself into, Ülgen Hatun.
But you weren't saying that out there.
Now I understand what you're doing
You are playing on me.
You can't hear what you're saying because
you're so hungry, Gürbüz Alp.
But am I like that?
Can hunger bend me?
Isn't it, Ülgen Hatun?
Nothing can twist
Cerkutay's wrist.
The world knows that.
Nothing can twist
Cerkutay's wrist.
Ülgen.
Your mother is here.
Why didn't you tell me?
I forgot about this, I forgot.
No, man, I don't think
she heard from there.
Right?
She is an old woman.
Yeah, she's old after all.
She must not have heard.
The dark midwife is here, too.
What does it mean?
Do they make the guest work?
Who is the guest?
What are you doing in
the kitchen, Gürbüz Alp?
I think fasting has affected you.
I came to set this lunatic at ease.
No, fasting did not affect me.
I eat a meal at suhoor that is
enough for me for ten days.
Mashallah!
What is this lunatic doing here?
You lunatic.
What do you do?
Yes, you, what are you doing?
Nothing.
Come on, don't look like that, come on.
Come on.
Come here.
Come on, get the pebbles out of these,
my eyes don't see well anymore.
I will, mother.
What are you doing? Give it
to me, Cerkutay.
Let him do it.
Isn't he crazy and standing like that
without work? Let him do it.
He can do this.
- You will, right?
- I will.
Go get the cheese curd dough.
He certainly does.
Fits very well in his hand.
Fits very well in his hand
With both hands, not with one hand!
Take it out with both hands, mix it up.
Do it.
They are waiting for food in the evening.
Gürbüz Alp.
Bring firewood for the stove.
This lunatic wouldn't do that.
He can't do it, he can't.
Right, this lunatic can't do it.
I am good at it.
Woods to the oven...
...and the lunatics into the fire! '
Right, Cerkutay?
Wooooddd...wooo...wood!
You'll see, you'll...
Here, have some.
You can't work with an empty stomach.
No, Cerkutay is fasting,
he doesn't want to eat!
Lunatics don't fast!
They just don't!
I'm fasting!
Fasting!
Girl!
Why does that lunatic keep following you?
He even brought you red cloth!
Esma!
We forgot to add salt!
I'll get the salt!
The salt!
What made you think
that you could fool me?
Go on!
Well, I will make you pay.
What made you think
that you could fool the Dark Midwife?
You don't even half the experience I have!
In the Name of Allah,
the Most Compassionate, the most Merciful
-In the Name of Allah,
Allah bless you.
Amen.
Let's eat.
Thank you.
Here you go.
Here, son.
In the Name of Allah,
the Most Compassionate, the most Merciful
May Allah give you prosperity.
Ali Aga, you did not have to prepare
such a table in a hard time like this.
As Prophet PBUH said...
...if a Muslim feeds another
hungry Muslim...
...Allah will feed that Muslim
with fruits in His heaven.
We have no hope left
in this world, my Bey.
It's enough for us if
we can have fruits in the afterlife.
Thank you, thank you, but...
...you can't just forget about this world
and focus on the fruits of the afterlife.
You have a son made of steel.
The future is theirs.
You won't leave this world without
planting a tree for them.
Muslims shouldn't fall into despair,
that's why...
...we will always stand together and
overcome these troubles, with the help of Allah.
I hope so.
So tell me...
These bandits, do they always bother you?
Always.
A brave man will always...
...stand against the oppressors
in these lands.
You will leave, but we have been
in these lands for years.
If we laugh one day, we cry for another 3.
All Aga, you know the best,
but those tears..
...might become water for a tree
you are going to plant for your children.
Maybe that brave man is your son.
We can't understand words with such wisdom, my lady.
But you are saying that there is
a purpose in the pain I suffer.
Ali Aga.
Your furnitures are missing.
I couldn't say it when
we were with the blacksmith.
His coin is not enough for the rent.
We keep helping each other.
As long as you support each other...
...with the help of Allah,
we can't be defeated.
Damascus.
Talay's Secret Base
Merchant.
Yes.
Too crowded for a merchant.
Why?
The relic we are carrying is
more valuable than anything.
We don't want to witness Nayman's wrath.
If this is fake..
...then you will witness my wrath.
Aren't you afraid?
I am afraid.
But I also ask the reason.
If he wanted to kill me...
...why did Nayman allow
me to go all this way?
He could have killed me right then.
You're right.
Nayman always takes precautions.
The letter describes the appearance
of the merchant.
Allah is the Greatest.
Allah hears whoever praises Him.
Peace be upon you and Allah's mercy.
Nayman said a gold bar was enough.
Is that right?
Not enough.
Pretty enough I think.
Open the door!
You have something that belongs to us.
Where's the seal?
I won't ask again.
Where's Cengiz Khan's seal?
I won’t tell you even if you kill me!
I'll take the seal eventually.
With or without you.
Wait.
Tell me Mongol.
Are you on his side or not?
Who are you?
I'm here in the name of Gazan Khan.
I am Commander Turgut Bey who serves
the ruler of the borders, Osman Bey.
Sultan Alaeddin sent a letter to
Gazan Khan.
He told us about Osman Bey and you.
He said Talay and Nayman will rebel.
I came to see it myself.
I guess...
...the letter was true.
So Bala Hatun fulfilled her duty.
Good.
If your words are true...
...now the rest will be taken care of us.
Still, what we need...
...is Cengiz Khan's seal...
He's a Mongol.
It won't take long to find what he hid.
In the Name of Allah,
the Most Compassionate, the most Merciful
Allah bless you my Bey.
May our fight be blessed my Bey.
May Allah bless you my Bey.
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
-May Allah bless you.
-Thank you.
-Konur.
-Yes my Bey?
Bring the ink and paper.
And you go back to the mansion.
As you wish my Bey.
Alaeddin. Orhan.
You stay with me.
My sheikh.
Take a seat.
Today I've walked among our people...
...in disguise of a public man.
But what I've seen...
...both made me sad...
...and lessened my hope.
...and optimistic.
What did you see my Bey?
Tradesmen don't have any business left.
While they can't even buy and sell,
Like everything was going okay...
...they're expected to pay rent.
Tell me.
What should we do sons?
While there are
such tough wars going on...
...those whoever are after money
should pay for it my bey.
The one who worries about their
wealth in this time shall lose their life.
During these times, my bey...
...we should look at the bigger picture.
Those people might just have the rent
as their income, as the trade won't work.
Are we going to protect the landlord
and disregard the tradesmen, brother?
I don't mean that.
A middle ground.
The tradesmen will declare their income.
And the landlord will decide the rent accordingly.
Expecting the amount of money that
the merchant barely earns...
...would be the end of the people.
So you're saying...
...while one struggle...
...the other won't be at ease.
Everyone will work together, you say.
The tradesmen's income will be proven too.
It won't be open to any misuse.
My sheikh...
...you heard them.
What do you think?
The student has surpassed the teacher,
Osman Bey.
They didn't leave anything else to say.
Both Orhan and Alaeddin
are right about what they've said.
But..
...what's important is...
...to find a middle ground.
And for that..
...two sides, just like your sons here...
...should come together.
..we'll find a middle ground.
Thank you my sheikh.
Thank you.
Take the pen.
Write down.
It's Osman Bey's law.
After the 20th of Ramadan...
...the amount of money
tradesmen earn will be counted.
And everyone will...
...give their rent accordingly to it.
If someone lies about their income...
...then they will...
...pay the price for it.
They will...
...be judged for earning haram money.
After every 20th of the each month...
...a statement will be taken from both sides...
...and they always will be checked.
From now in it's Osman Bey's law.
It will be applied.
My sheikh.
I'm being called lunatic now!
The Dark Midwife hates me, too...
What am I going to do now?
Perhaps I should...
...go up to her...
...and say that...
..."Hatun Hatun I'm not lunatic!"...
I should say that...
Say that...
that I...
...that I have feelings for your
daughter Ulgen.
I can't do that either.
She thinks that I'm lunatic
but she's more lunatic than me.
She will do much more
than just hitting me on the head.
What am I going to do?
I'm going to make her like me.
But she even likes Gurbuz
more than she likes me.
Are you waiting for Suhoor, lunatic boy?
You're the only lunatic person
I know that fasts.
I'm half lunatic
How can a lunatic be half lunatic?
You either need to be completely
insane or completely sane.
Dealing in halves
will not do any good to you.
Now...
...since you're half insane
and half sane...
Yes.
You're going to help me.
What do you want from the lunatic?
I want a groom.
What?
I said that I wanted a groom,
can't you hear?
For whom?
For you?
You lunatic, stop the nonsense!
I'd give you a nice beating
now if you weren't crazy.
For whom do you think?
For my daughter.
Watch out!
So you're going to help me.
A brave..
...very smart...
I said smart, alright? Not lunatic.
Valiant...
...really strong...
That's the husband you're going to
find for my daughter.
This is a kind of man Ulgen deserves.
Watch out!
So you are in love...
...with my daughter, lunatic boy...
Then you're about to
go through a tough test.
In the Name of Allah,
the Most Compassionate, the most Merciful
Thank you.
Do you know Hizir PBUH?
But don't you call me Hizir, Turgut Bey.
People might expect miracles from me.
We keep asking you how you
found Genghis Khan's seal..
...but you don't tell us anything.
How do we know if you're
really not full of miracles?
My name is neither Hizir nor
I can do any miracles.
I'm just a Mongol
who's been honored with Islam.
-That's the secret to it.
-Eyvallah.
It's about being well-protected.
Anyway...
...we shouldn’t give you further trouble.
Knowing that you're safe is enough.
Thank Allah that...
...the mission I was given included
Suhoor with such brave men.
Thank you.
Thank you, as well.
It's an honor to share a meal with you.
Alps, let's finish Suhoor...
...and we will
hit the road after the morning prayer.
We will first pick up Bayindir...
... and then, if Allah permits,
our destination is Yenisehir.
Okay, my Bey.
Turgut Bey and his men...
...are on a mission
beyond the borders of Seljuk.
They must have obtained
Genghis Khan's seal by now.
They have crossed a tough road, my Bey.
They did, they actually did.
But..
...this is such a seal that...
...it is strong enough to gather all
the Mongolian Beys under one flag.
If Nayman and Talay gets
their hands on it...
...then they will want to remove
Muslims from these lands.
My Bey, the seal will weaken Nayman
when we have it.
But what strength will it bring to us?
If we lose it and they have it...
Don't say that, my Bey.
Fortunetaly...
...Bala Hatun went to Sultan Alaeddin,
and wrote a letter to Gazan Khan.
Thanks to this letter, a Mongol commander
will come here with Turgut Bey.
He'll have the seal.
That Commander will stop Nayman.
We killed them in Konya.
If Allah permits,
we'll end them in our lands as well, my Bey.
For sure.
For sure, we will.
Turan.
What's the situation in the field?
My Bey. There is no traps.
The field is flat.
Both sides have the same advantage.
Did you find the base?
Their locations are known, my Bey.
Then sent Alps there at sunrise.
When they move, alps will attack.
As you wish my Bey.
Now...
...eat well in Suhoor tonight.
Tomorrow, the biggest war this land
has ever seen will come to life.
My Bey.
What about us?
Sons...
...you have a different mission.
You will guard the bazaar
according to Osman Bey's order.
We won't let those bandits make a move.
As you wish my Bey.
Come on.
Come.
Peace be with you, Ali Aga.
Peace be upon you too.
The shop is now yours.
Osman Bey has bought
the shop in your name.
Enjoy it!
Osman Bey?
-Have a good day.
-Thank you.
Hear me out!
Osman Bey's new law commands...
...that after the the 20th day of Ramadan..
The law will help the traders
get back on their feet!
Indeed.
And once we defeat Nayman...
...both the tradesmen and the trading
will come to life.
Let’s not keep the ones
who are in need waiting, my Beys.
There are still many
houses we need to visit.
Yenisehir, Osman Bey's Mansion.
Osman.
Nayman has tried to trap you before,
using Orhan.
He will try to do something
shady in this fight too.
Do you think that
he will cheat again?
I do, my Bala.
He'll definitely cheat again.
You know he cheats yet you accept
his duel invitation!
He trusts his cheats.
But I trust my Allah first,
then to my own strength.
May Allah make their plans fail, my Bey.
Be cautious.
Amen, Bala.
Amen, my dear.
Bala, until now, you have always
supported my dream.
Thank you.
Give me your blessings.
If I fall...
...keep my dream alive.
What does that mean, Osman?
I give you my blessing, but may Allah
not allow you to be defeated.
May He let you live long enough to see
your dream come true with your children.
Amen.
Look what Bayindir did!
Look what that dog did!
He played some tricks again, and escaped!
My Bey, forgive us, we just...
You just what?
All you had to do was to keep an eye on
a man tied to a tree!
What have you done?
Tell me, how did he escape?
What were you doing?
I will ask about this again in Yenisehir..
But I will make Bayindir pay for this.
Even if he asks for forgiveness,
I will not forgive him!
I will turn his life into hell!
Tell me, is there any traces?
My Bey, there is a river on this side,
there are traces over there.
It looks like they went that way.
What’s on your mind, Turgut Bey?
We got what we want from Bayindir, but...
...if he reaches Nayman before us...
...then all or plans will be for nothing.
We need to go quickly.
Quickly! Come on alps!
We will ride for homeland!
We won't stop to rest!
If Osman Bey doesn't learn about this in time,
we won't have a homeland we can return!
Come on!
My Bey is coming, be quick alps!
Brothers!
Our weapons will be drenched
in Mongolian blood today.
Today is Nayman's last day, I can feel it.
Brothers!
May your swords be sharp, may your spears
be strong, and your hearts brave!
Alps.
Today I made a deal with Nayman.
We will battle.
As the name implies...
This field is called men's field!
We don't know what Nayman
ordered his warriors.
But you...
...you will never give up on your duty.
Today we will bury Nayman
and his army in this land.
Okay my Bey.
For sure, my Bey!
Now listen to me.
For sure...
For sure, our plan is decent.
But.
...if things don't go the way we want...
...and fate...
...has decided I become a martyr...
...don't be frightened and turn back on your duty.
You will destroy those bases.
You will protect the people.
Even if I fall a martyr...
...that Nayman...
...won't leave this land alive!
And the last thing he hears will be...
Allah is the Greatest!
My Bey.
Kargun tribe's Alps are in position waiting for you.
.Why are we waiting Aktemur?
Let’s leave.
My Bey, people approaching.
I won’t let you leave.
Are they here to stop us Aktemur?
Is there something wrong?
We were waiting for you.
I sat on the post as you wished.
Thank you my nephew.
But...
...you kicked me out of the assembly...
...they think I'm the enemy.
Let them.
Let them so that th enemy can find you.
Mother Sultan and the others..
...those who are secretly enemies...
...might come to you now.
Thank you my Bey.
What's my next duty?
Your next duty...
...is...
...Marmaracik.
You'll take Marmaracik.
Nayman must have heard you betrayed me.
He'll think I'm alone now.
When I start the battle with him,
Marmaracik...
....will be defenseless.
He won't think we'll attack there.
Son.
For the blood of the soldier
whose post you sit on.
Do it for Oktem Bey.
As you wish my Bey.
Kargun's soldiers have been waiting for this.
Allah is with us. Victory is ours.
Go in peace son.
Sisters, let's go.
Osman Bey sends his regards Aktemur.
Peace be upon him.
These are yours.
Mongol warriors' clothes.
Tell me Aktemur Bey.
Why didn't you tell us
you spoke to your uncle?
It’s my duty mother.
Don't be down about it.
No one but my uncle knows.
So Osman Bey knew you
were going to be sit on the throne.
But I don't get it.
Why did you not reveal it?
My uncle doesn't trust Ismihan.
Thinks she will stab us in the back
the first chance she gets.
Mother Sultan would want to use my mother
and you the first chance she gets.
Don't be mad Alcicek.
Of course I won't.
You thought well.
Now...
He doesn't think we will attack the castle.
The castle will be open to any attack.
Once the last unity gets out...
...we'll go in.
Then we will use the hidden passages.
Alcicek knows the way.
She'll show you the way.
Praise be!
A daughter in law
has to be like this, right?
Don't worry.
We won't reveal your secret.
We'll go and get out secretly.
Even the alps of Kargun Tribe...
...won't see us.
So that you can keep your
secret with Osman Bey.
Be careful.
You'll attack once
we go in and give the sign.
Come on.
May our fight be blessed!
Come on sisters!
Daughter in law.
You come with us too.
As you wish, Hatun The Sister.
Come on then Kutlu.
Shaman!
The poison.
Osman...
...with every possible ending...
...I'm the one who wins.
Pour it.
I can't see, Commander Nayman!
Osman’s blind eye...
...will be my strongest weapon.
Soldiers!
Osman dies today..
..and then his whole family will follow.
Karancul!
Bayindir should arrive soon.
Prepare letters to be sent out
to all Mongol cities!
Once Bayindir brings the seal here...
...we will send out the letters.
As you command, Commander Nayman.
Osman will' not live long enough...
...to see me rule over these lands!
I will erase the word
Turk from all over these lands!
I will rule the world...
...with my mighty army!
Follow me!
We're leaving!
Get down!
Let's go!
My Bey, as you commanded...
... Boranand the archer Alps have positioned
behind Nayman and his soldiers.
Karancu is in charge of
the forces at the base.
He will water these lands
with blood once Osman is dead!
Are you ready Osman?
I am ready!
I have been waiting for
this moment for a long time!
Did you give orders to your Beys?
When you die, they will come
and kneel before me.
If what you say happens...
...they will do that.
But when I take your head...
...Tell me, will your soldiers
leave these lands?
It's impossible for you to defeat me.
...but they will leave if you do.
They will leave.
They will.
But those strong warriors of yours...
...don't have any chance against my alps.
The warriors behind me...
...have been on the road for years.
My warriors were born in the steppe lands,
they were scorched in the deserts.
...they were washed in lakes
and they died in battles.
They became strong!
You are not strong like iron!
The warriors you call iron..
...have been defeated by us many times.
Don't worry.
My alps will always defeat your warriors.
Then let's fight your alps and my soldiers!
Let's warm the field a little
before our fight!
Send 3 alps.
What is it?
Are you scared of death?
Why aren't you fighting yourself?
I want to watch my warriors
tear your alps apart.
Okay.
Let's do it.
Mother Sultan, forgive me, but...
...Even while Sultan Alaeddin agreed
to be allies with Osman Bey...
Why aren't we on the battlefield?
That's the point, Celali.
I thought Osman helped us
sincerely and protected me.
But he was always planning
his secret move.
They always have a secret goal.
First, they took Sultan's support,
then the letter to Gazan Khan.
But I won't be used, Celali..
...I am the one who uses!
From now on, even the most precious
person in these lands...
...will be nothing but a tool for me!
Sisters, be cautious. We won't move
until Aktemur and alps enter the castle.
Come on.
There is a stone here.
Give it to me.
What are you doing Alcicek?
There is a rope under this rock,
it will open the door.
It's open.
Come on.
Let's go.
My Bey. I know all their tricks.
Let me beat them.
My Bey.
Allow me to fight.
Allow me to battle them.
My Bey. Allow me to crush
them like a lion.
My Bey. Let me attack
them like a wolf.
My Bey. Let my mace
feed on infidel blood.
Konur.
Turahan.
Osman Bey.
You always choose an Alp.
Let me show you how Beys fight.
Let me bring you
the corpses of these infidels.
Bayram Bey.
Come on then.
Thank you valiants. Go on.
Kaucube. Kara Noyan.
Nogay!
Warriors!
May your swords break bones.
You are Erlik Han's wrath!
Allah is the Greatest!
Thank you, my valiant.
Thank you.
Turahan.
Allah is the greatest!
Thank you, my valiant.
Thank you.
EyvAllah.
Bayram Bey.
This is how you all will end up!
I was brave huh alps?
Very much, Bayram Bey.
Very much.
What happened?
Why did you come back?
Answer.
Speak.
Now.
You're all going to die.
Alps.
Today is the day we fight!
Come on.
Come on Bala.
Let's take down those dogs!
In the Name of Allah!
It's now in your hands, Commander Bagatur.
May Allah help you.
Nayman's evildoing
does not only affect us...
It affects all Muslims!
I'm going to stop him,
Turgut Bey. Don't worry.
Thank you.
May your fight be blessed.
We're leaving, alps!
Let's go.
Come here, you dogs!
Come on!
So we did conquer Marmaracik, my Bey.
We did, Hatun.
We did.
We've avenged our martyrs!
Marmaracik is ours!
Allah is the Greatest!
Whose victory do you think will
benefit us the most, Mother Sultan.
What difference does it make?
Whoever survives will leave the battlefield weak.
Whoever wins...
...will become my prisoner.
I'm the only ruler of these lands.
I bear witness that there is none
worthy of worship, Allah..
...and I bear witness that Mohammad
is His servant and messenger.
To Allah we belong and to Him we all shall return.
Come to me.
The beginning of the end, Osman...
The beginning of your end, Nayman.
Your end.
The last thing you hear...
...will be the chants of my soldiers...
...who will kill your whole family, Osman.
It's enough, Osman.
Warriors!
Allah is the Greatest!
Brought to you by historicalfuntv.com